# YASH TULSIANI

## CONTACT

ytulsiani.com

**♥** REDACTED

in ytulsiani

ytulsiani

**SKILLS** 

Languages: Java, Python, Bash, Go, JavaScript, C,

Assembly, SQL

Technologies: Cloud Foundry, Chef, Openstack, Concourse CI, AWS, GCP, Heroku, Unity, Android Studio, Pivotal Tracker, Jira

Frameworks and Libraries: NodeJS, JavaFX, OpenCV, HashiCorp Tools

Concepts: Agile, Continuous Integration, Automated Testing, Test Driven Development, Pair Programming, Platform as a Service, Infrastructure as Code

# **ACTIVITIES**

#### College of Computing Tutor

Tutor for students taking Computer Science courses at Georgia Tech including Data Structures and Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, and Systems Programming.

## Georgia Tech Communications

Created content for Georgia Tech's social media platforms including their official Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, and Snapchat. Content included photos, videos, graphics, and articles that Georgia Tech used to promote campus life.

## GreyHat Infosec

Used tools like Metasploit and Wireshark to see how penetration testing is done in the field by deploying vulnerable Linux VMs on my system.

#### Vibha · President

Helped start a Georgia Tech chapter for an organization raising funding and awareness for education for children in developing countries. Led club of 15 volunteers to host multiple successful awareness events and campaigns that raised thousands of dollars.

Tech The Halls · Vice President of Marketing Worked in executive board for an organization promoting inner-city education through connections. Responsible for finding innovative ways to increase mentor, student, and corporate sponsor awareness. Developed website for the club on bootstrap located at tech the halls. gtorg. gatech. edu.

# FouroFour Co · Visual Artist

Worked in creating visual content for local Atlanta brands to market their company and products.

#### Atlanta Humane Society

Volunteered at a humane society in dog rehabilitation and adoption center. Took photos of the adoptions animals and managed their website with new animals.

## Subaru Ambassador

Help promote the Subaru brand at different events and on social media.

## **EDUCATION**

Georgia Institute of Technology B.S. Computer Science August 2015 - May 2019 High Honors, Dean's List, GPA: 3.27 Tutor for the College of Computing

# **EMPLOYMENT**

REDACTED

Software Engineer

San Francisco, CA Aug. 2019 to Current

San Francisco, CA

• Returning as a full-time engineer on a Cloud Foundry team

Software Engineering Intern

May 2018 to Aug. 2018 • Worked on a release integration system supporting open source Cloud Foundry (my work is publicly available on

- Improved the reliability of Cloud Foundry's flakiest tests in Go
- Created CI pipelines to improve the agility of component teams deploying on the platform

Mailchimp Systems Engineering Intern

Atlanta, GA Aug. 2018 to Dec. 2018

• Worked on an internal datacenter management tool to support internal and production applications

• Migrated RPC system from Apache Thrift to gRPC and integrated it into a Django Python app

Ultimate Software

Weston, FL

Software Engineering Intern

- May 2017 to Aug. 2017 • Worked in a devops role for Platform as a Service team supporting Pivotal Cloud Foundry
- Developed pipelines for continuous integration and automation for tasks such as SQL auto-recovery and backup on critical user data
- · Migrated Chef deployments to Bosh with Ruby and Python to speed up deployment time for development teams
- Created tools to manage virtual machines on Openstack

Home Depot

Software Engineering Intern

May 2016 to Aug. 2016

- Developed Proof of Concept allowing for the development of an integrated backend over multiple store fronts with Javascript and Angular to allow Home Depot to have a single interface for multiple store fronts
- Helped decrease content deployment time from days to hours

PhD Founders

Schaumburg, IL Sept. 2014 to Feb. 2017

Founder

- Started a tutoring company to provide low cost tutoring to over 30 students ranging from first grade to college
- Managed 3 employees and developed a sustainable business plan

# **PROJECTS**

# My Angel Sight

Built a tool that analyzes if a driver is distracted while on the road. Used OpenCV to detect a person along with a convolution neural network to analyze their facial features. Hosted using Google Cloud Functions. 1st place winner and sponsor prize winner at HackAubrun 2019. Project details at myangelsight.com.

### Computer Science Creativity

Wrote a Medium article discussing the benefits of having a creative hobby in computer science. The article was featured on multiple tech news sites and blogs, including the front page of Hacker News. The article is published at bit.ly/csCreativity.

#### Undergraduate Research: iTrans

Implemented machine learning algorithms in Python connected to a MySQL database to predict bus arrival and departures for Georgia Tech's busing system. These algorithms will be used to provide accurate readings for the campus busing arrival estimator API.

#### Audio AD

Developed **Unity application** as a proof of concept for an audio centric software and hardware suite to help filmmakers focus on their work without having to micromanage their crew. Details on the project, including demo videos are available at github.com/ytulsiani/Audio-AD.

#### MauledBy

Developed website to raise money for the ACLU that generates gifs with an image uploaded by the user. Software used to build this includes NodeJS, Python, and OpenCV. Website is live at bit.ly/2uxzaEW and the code is available at github.com/ytulsiani/Trump-WWE.